cgpress.org 2016-05-09

# Privacy Policy - CGPress

### Privacy Policy Contents

1\. Introduction, Acceptance, and General Statements Regarding Privacy and the Privacy Policy  
2\. Information Collection and Use  
3\. Consent  
4\. Compliance with the Law and Other Cases of Disclosure of Personal Information  
5\. Access to Personal Information  
6\. Protecting Personal Information  
7\. Personal Information and the Internet  
8\. Transfer of Personal Information to Third Parties Under Limited Circumstances  
9\. Transfer of Non-personally Identifiable Information to Third Parties Under Limited Circumstances  
10\. Compliance with Privacy Laws  
11\. Limitation of Liability  
12\. Comments, Questions and Requests  

### 1\. Introduction, Acceptance, and General Statement Regarding Privacy and the Privacy Policy

Welcome to the CGPress Website located at http://cgpress.org/ (the “Website”) which includes all subdomains present and future. We hope you enjoy your visit and / or use of the Website. By visiting and / or using the Website, you agree to be bound by the terms of the present agreement, known as the Privacy Policy (the “Policy”). 

CGPress is owned and operated by Delicate Machines Graphics Inc. (“DMGI”), a duly-incorporated business located in Nova Scotia, Canada. Where the present Policy refers to “CGPress”, it may refer to CGPress (and / or its agents or representatives) or DMGI (and / or its officers, directors, employees, agents or representatives) or both, depending on the context. In the present Policy, CGPress may be referred to as “we” or “us” and Website visitors may be referred to as “you” or “your”, whether individually or collectively. 

The Policy was last modified on July 16, 2014. CGPress reserves the right, at any time and without prior notice, to modify or replace any of the Policy. Any changes to the Policy can be found at this URL. It is your responsibility to check the Policy periodically for changes. Your use of the Website following the posting of any changes to the Policy constitutes acceptance of those changes.

The Policy should be read in conjunction with the [Terms and Conditions](http://cgpress.org/terms_and_conditions), as both these documents govern your use of the Website.

CGPress takes your privacy and security of personal information very seriously. We have provided a secure environment and this strict Policy that describes the limited ways the information is used and the limited access to such information.

Personal information is hereby defined as information about an identifiable individual, but does not include the name, title or business address or telephone number of an employee of an organization. This Policy covers personal information collected by CGPress through your use of the Website and controlled by CGPress. 

This Policy does not apply to the general practices and treatment of information (whether personal or not) by third parties that CGPress does not own or control, including but not limited to any third party websites or services that you elect to access through the Website or via a link from the Website (“third party website”), or to individuals that CGPress does not manage or employ. While we attempt to facilitate access or link to only to those third party websites that share our respect for your privacy, we cannot take responsibility for the content or privacy policies of those third party websites. We encourage you to carefully review the privacy policies of any third party websites you access. We have named and provided links to the most important of these third party websites further in this Policy.

This Policy does not cover any personal information you send to CGPress via any non-secured mode of communications such as email, instant messenger or Twitter, as communications via these methods may be subject to interception, loss, or alteration. While we welcome your comments and suggestions sent to us in this manner, we encourage you to carefully examine what personal information you send to CGPress via these methods.

### 2\. Information Collection and Use

CGPress is a site dedicated to journalism. As such, most of our collection, use and disclosure of personal information is done for journalistic purposes. In order to operate our site, we may collect and process the following information:

– Non-personally identifiable information: derived from visits to our site or any resources used on our site, such as pages requested, duration of visits to the site, etc. This information is used in aggregated form to assess our organization’s performance and how we can improve our content. Statistical, non-personal information, such as which news items or feature articles are most requested collectively in a given month is used to further enhance the site and may be shared with third parties or the public itself, as described more fully further down in this Policy. 

– Non-personally identifiable information: cookies, which are small pieces of data sent from a website and stored in a user’s web browser, are used to allow visitors to customize their site experience. By using the Website you consent to their use. This setting remains in the user’s browser and is at no point tied to personally identifiable information. Users of the site may block the use cookies by choosing the appropriate settings in their respective browsers. More information on the nature of cookies and how to block them is available on the [WikiHow website](http://www.wikihow.com/Disable-Cookies), or from your Browser’s Help function.

– Personal information: data provided by you voluntarily by filling out forms on our site, like submitting comments or news contributions. This may include, without limitation, your name and email. This information will be used for daily duties related to the site’s journalistic purposes. We may use your email to contact you regarding news or comments you have submitted to the site, to confirm or request further information related to a news item, or for other non-frequent site-related matters. At no point will we subscribe you automatically to unrequested site-related email lists without your explicit consent.

When receiving news contributions, we credit sources of news items we receive and post them in news items publicly with a link to their sites. This is important for ensuring transparency and independence in news reporting and stimulating readers to control that no commercial interests are interfering with published news. Contributors are explicitly asked for their consent to allow the names they enter in the news contribution forms to be displayed as sources and are also given an option to opt out of it; we dutifully respect contributors that explicitly request not to be mentioned by filling out the form in the way described in the [“Contribute News” page](http://cgpress.org/contribute). Contributors of news acknowledge and agree that their submitted personal and / or organization’s information may be published on the Website for this purpose, as described more fully on the Contribute News page. 

– Personal information: information given to us when you contact us for any reason. This information will only be used for the purpose you contacted us for, including replying to your emails and other site-related matters, with journalism as its main purpose.

– Business information or personal information related to business activities: data provided by you voluntarily by filling out the form for requesting information for advertising at this site, or for other business-related purposes, as well as information given to us by you for business related activities through means other than filling out forms. This information will only be used for the purpose you contacted us for, including replying to your emails, providing you with information you requested and other matters related to commercial activities performed at the site.

We do not sell or rent personally identifiable information about you to any third party companies. At no point will we subscribe you automatically to unrequested site-related email lists without your explicit consent. Certain information about you (including personal information) may be transferred to third parties, but only to the very limited circumstances described further down in this Policy.

### 3\. Consent

In obtaining consent, the reasonable expectations of individuals are relevant. Voluntarily filling forms for posting comments is considered implied consent for storing that information electronically and publishing it on the site. In cases in which disclosure of information could be considered sensitive, we will seek to obtain explicit consent for this disclosure, and will provide an option to opt out.

Voluntarily filling forms for contacting us on business-related matters or requesting business-related information is considered implied consent for collecting that information electronically and using that information for emailing you replies to your messages and requests for information.

For personal information that is not related to journalistic purposes you may withdraw consent for its collection, use and disclosure at any time, subject to legal or contractual restrictions and reasonable notice. Your withdrawal of consent to our collection, use and disclosure of your personal information may impact our ability to transact with you, whether for business purposes or otherwise.

### 4\. Compliance with the Law and Other Cases of Disclosure of Personal Information

CGPress retains the right to disclose personal information if required to do so by law, if we need to respond to or comply with legal requirements, exercise our legal rights or defend against legal claims, protect the safety or property of our readers or the public, take action regarding potentially threatening or illegal activities, if we believe it is necessary to investigate, prevent, or take action regarding situations that involve abuse of the Website infrastructure or the Internet in general, if we believe it is necessary to investigate violations of CGPress’ Terms and Conditions or this Policy, or if the information is already publicly known or as otherwise required by law.

We may also disclose personal information to a parent company, subsidiaries, joint ventures, or other companies under common control with CGPress (in which case we will require such entities to honour this Policy), or if CGPress is acquired by or merged with another entity (in which case we will require such entity to assume our obligations under this Policy, or inform you that you are covered by a new privacy policy).

### 5\. Access to Personal Information

With regards to personal information not related to journalistic purposes you have the right to be informed of the existence, use and disclosure of this personal information and be given access to this information (subject to certain exceptions prescribed by law). You can challenge the accuracy and completeness of the information and have it amended as appropriate. You may also request the permanent deletion of your personal information. For this purpose you may be required to provide sufficient information to permit us to provide an account of the existence, use, and disclosure of personal information. The request must be directed to the company’s Privacy Officer, at the address further down in this Policy. Please note that we may charge a minimal fee for retrieval and copying of your personal information. If this represents an extensive workload, we will notify you of the amount of this minimal fee prior to fulfilling your request

### 6\. Protecting Personal Information

Personal information provided to us is protected through the use of various security measures. These include the use of security software, internal passwords and restricted physical and electronic access to certain information. In addition, CGPress uses third party vendors and hosting partners to provide the necessary hardware, software, networking, storage, and related technology required to run the Website, and these third parties have been selected for their high standards of security.

### 7\. Personal Information and the Internet

Due to the nature of online transmission of information, it’s important to keep in mind that no transmission over the Internet is 100% secure. It is thus advisable to avoid sending sensitive personal information over the Internet as much as possible. While we place an emphasis on protecting personal information, we cannot warrant the security of any information you transmit to us over the Internet. You acknowledge and agree that CGPress cannot be held responsible for damages resulting from the transmission of confidential information or personal information over the Internet and that such communications are at your own risk.

### 8\. Transfer of Personal Information to Third Parties Under Limited Circumstances

CGPress uses certain third party services in order to augment the Website. Personal information may be transferred from CGPress to these third party services, but only to the extent required in order for them to function properly, and only upon your express submission of such information. These third party services are limited to [Facebook](http://www.facebook.com/), [Twitter](http://www.twitter.com/), and [Google+](http://plus.google.com/) for sharing of Website content. If you are not already logged in to those third party services, your personal information required to login to those accounts is transferred securely from CGPress to the third party services. When your personal information is transferred to these third party services, it is covered by their respective privacy policies, which we encourage you to read.

### 9\. Transfer of Non-personally Identifiable Information to Third Parties Under Limited Circumstances

CGPress may transfer certain non-personally identifiable information as described in this section, but only for the very limited purposes described.

CGPress automatically collects certain information using a third-party analytics program to help us understand how our users use the Website, but none of this information identifies you personally. For example, each time you visit the Website we automatically collect your IP address, browser and computer type, access times, the web page from which you came, and the web page(s) you access (as applicable). We use information collected in this manner only to better understand your needs and the needs of the Website users in the aggregate. CGPress also makes use of information gathered for statistical purposes to keep track of the number of visits to the Website and which pages on the Website with a view to introducing improvements.

CGPress uses a third-party program in order to deliver advertisements to the Website. When you click on an advertisement, certain information may be transferred to third party advertisers, but none of this information identifies you personally. This information may include the name of the Website, the date and time you clicked the advertisement, your IP address, and a unique string of data which does not identify you personally.

### 10\. Compliance with Privacy Laws

This Policy and CGPress’ practices in general are designed to be in compliance with Canada’s Personal Information Protection and Electronic Documents Act (“PIPEDA”, S.C. 2000, c. 5). If you have any questions regarding this compliance, please contact us using the contact information further down in this Policy.

### 11\. Limitation of Liability

CGPress, and / or its respective officers, directors, owners, officials, partners, partnerships, principals, employees, affiliates and other related entities, servants, agents, representatives, successors and assigns, will not be held liable for any damages resulting from the misuse of any information collected by any third party, or any misuse of any information collected through the Website not in violation of the Policy.

### 12\. Comments, Questions and Requests

For any comments, questions, requests to view, modify or delete your personal information held by CGPress, or other subjects related to our Privacy Policy or privacy practices please contact our Privacy Officer at the following email address: [privacy@cgpress.org](mailto:privacy@cgpress.org), or by mail at 10 Benview Drive, Dartmouth, Nova Scotia, Canada, B2Y 1W5.

© CGPress 2014
